Today.
NASA's James Webb Space Telescope amazes
us with its new views of the universe,
but its images
build upon 40 years of innovation
in infrared space telescopes.
The universe is full of infrared light
at wavelengths much longer
than what human eyes can see.
We need space
telescopes equipped with special detectors
to reveal these hidden wonders.
The first
was the Infrared Astronomical Satellite,
or IRAS,
launched in 1983.
IRAS measured
the infrared glow of hundreds
of thousands of stars and galaxies.
In 2003,
the Spitzer Space Telescope began
a new era of infrared astronomy.
Spitzer revealed details of galaxies
and nebulas
never seen before.
Now Webb takes us even deeper
into the infrared universe.
We look forward to the wonders yet
to be revealed by Webb
and future infrared telescopes.